Jinhyuk Yoon

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I am an engineer creates inspirational experience and pragmatic solution through technology. I love interacting with people through various project such as research, design, art work, and education. With my major background and experiences, I've been trying to embrace and create meaningful work.

Professional Experience

Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances Division

Jan 2019 – Present

Mechanical Design Intern

Using user analysis, optimize standard of hinge damper for slow-closing in the oven door.

Sovoro Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Communications Manager

Conducted UI/UX design of the service, catalog design, market research, and business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity May 2016 - Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed scientific street performance, and acted scientific play targeting adults as a finalist of FameLab Korea and science communicator commissioned by minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center

Aug 2017 - Oct 2017

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant Robot, inspired by Anklebot.

Leadership Experience

POSTECH, Student Election Committee

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

Student President

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Regular application was fully booked in 50 seconds after opening. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

2014 - Present

Bachelor Thesis Project - Book Borrowing Robot Minor - Industrial Management Engineering Expect to graduate with *Magna Cum Laude*

Awards and Honors

| Commission Letter Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator | 2016 |
|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|----------------|
| Finalist Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 rd FameLab Korea | 2016 |
| Runners up Artience Creation Challenge 30x30, 30 hours Hackathon project, hosted by British Council | 2017 |
| Honorable Mention 3 Minute Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH | 2015 |
| Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering | 2015, 2016 |
| The 4 th Prize The 2 nd POSTECH Hackathon | 2016 |
| National Academic Excellence Scholarship Korea Student Aid Foundation | 2016 – Present |
| KT&G Foundation Scholarship POSTECH | 2016 |
| Jigok Scholarship POSTECH | 2014 - 2016 |

Skills and Tools

Programming Language

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

Graphic Design

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

Selected Talks

| Keynote Speech, "About Experience" , POSTECH Alumni Conference for Freshman, Pohang | 2018 |
|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|------|
| Keynote Speech, "Engineering and Science Communication", The 5th Integrated Science Leading Teacher Training, Yeongcheon | 2016 |
| Keynote Speech, "About Science Communication", National Youth Science Exploration Competition, Gyeongju | 2016 |
| Talk, " <i>Regain the lost life</i> ", Suseong-gu Gosan Library , Daegu | 2018 |
| Talk, "Regain the lost life", KIST Science Station, Seoul | 2017 |
| Talk, "Space food", The 13th Bohyeonsan Starlight Festival, Yeongcheon | 2016 |
| Talk, "Science, Engineering and Me", Seongji Highschool, Yongin | 2017 |
| Talk, "Communicate with Science", Mulgeum High School, Yangsan | 2017 |
| Talk, "Talk with Odd Engineering Student", Samsung Girl's High School, Busan | 2017 |